

Sreekanth Vinodkumar

(+1) 2269610843 **Date of birth**: 26/05/1998 **Gender:** Male

Email address: 25sreekanth@gmail.com

Website: https://sreekanth98.netlify.app/

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sreekanth-v-9b0109142/

• Address: 343 Cameron Ave, N9B1Y8 windsor (Canada)

ABOUT ME

Looking forward to earning a part-time position as a Software developer at an organization where I can apply my technical skills in coding and software design to generate high-end solutions to general software issues along with drawing a better user experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer

Riafy Technologies [26/05/2020 - 11/2021]

City: Kochi
Country: India

Full-stack developer experienced in Node.js and React.js

Software engineer

Qburst Technologies [08/11/2021 - 29/07/2022]

City: Kochi Country: India

Software engineer with expertise in Python, HTML, CSS, Node.js, React.js.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master of Applied Computing specialisation in Artificial Intelligence

University of Windsor [09/2022 - Current]

Address: Windsor, N9B1Y8 Ontario (Canada)

https://www.uwindsor.ca

Bachelor of Technology(Honours) in Computer Science and Engineering

A P J Abdul Kalam Technological University [01/08/2016 - 31/07/2020]

Address: Mar Athanasius College of Engineering, 686666 Kothamangalam (India)

http://www.mace.ac.in/ Final grade : CGPA - 8.08

Higher Secondary Education

Holy Cross Higher Secondary School [01/06/2014 – 31/03/2016]

Address: 686584 Kottayam (India)

Final grade: 92.75%

Secondary Education

Gayathri Central School [01/06/2013 – 31/03/2014]

Address: 686573 Kottayam (India)

Final grade: CGPA - 9.2

PROJECTS

Working model of Self-driving Vehicle

[2020]

A self-driving vehicle embedded with a convolutional neural network and shortest path algorithm for predicting the best path and direction which enables safe travel from one location to another.

TicTacToe puzzle Game Android App

[2020]

Tic-tac-toe is a game for 2 players, X and O, who take turns marking the spaces in a 3×3 grid. The player who succeeds in placing three of their marks in a horizontal, vertical, or diagonal row is the winner. Features include Single player (play with android) with two difficulty levels and Multiplayer

Speech Text Converter Android App

[2020]

An android app for voice to text and text to voice conversion. Build-in TTS engine for text to speech conversion and androids built-in speech recogniser to convert speech into text.

Life Source - Blood Bank Management System

[2018]

A simple and efficient system for Blood bank management. This system has a real-time geo-powered network of blood donors which allows the hospital to search directly for nearby blood donors thus reducing the middle-man and saving time.

Personal diary application

[10/2021 - 12/2021]

A simple personal diary with an attractive UI with multiple themes.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Building complete system using ReactJs, NodeJs and MongoDB. Implementation of a fully functional text editor.
- Multiple themes selecting functionality.
- Database architecture and saving text editor data in MongoDB. JWT token implementation for security.

https://diary-website.netlify.app

Logistics Application

[07/2020 - 11/2020]

The goal of this web app is to enable users to check available vehicles to transport logistics from one location to another. When a user requests transportation of goods then the nearest vehicle is allocated to the user. The system also helps to track the vehicle throughout the journey.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Responsive UI using native CSS and media query.
- Downloading reports and transaction details.

- Google map implementation and tracking of vehicles.
- Implementation of firebase push notification.
- Multi-Language functionality and RTL implementation for corresponding languages.
- Enabled service workers for notifications when the website is not active or closed.

Food Delivery System

[04/2020 - 08/2020]

The scope of the project is to develop a chef and foodie applications, as well as a dashboard for system administrators to manage the system. Foodies can order menus or dishes from a chef instantly or arrange a bulk order for an event. This system also enables the chef to host a food event and invite other chefs and foodies.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Responsive UI using native CSS and media query.
- Implementation of different kinds of charts in the dashboard using ChartJS.
- Implementation of multiple filters and downloading reports in excel format.

Online Shopping System

[03/2021 - 08/2021]

The scope of the project is to develop an application for users to order vegetables and meat, as well as an application for pickers who collect and pack products to make them ready for delivery, and an application for drivers who deliver the product. Apart from these applications, there are consoles to manage the system.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Responsive UI using native CSS and media query.
- Implementation of charts in the console to represent data in an efficient way.
- Implementation of dark and light themes.
- Develop Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Management Information System (MIS), and Logistics Management (LCM) consoles.

Workspace for Companies Project

[10/2021 - 07/2022]

The purpose of this system is to allow companies or professional teams to reserve private rooms, conference rooms or benches to use as workspaces. Rooms can be rented to companies based on the availability. This system is basically Airbnb for companies.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Responsive UI for admin dashboard.
- Implementation of automatic validation and error reporting when a details-filled sheet is uploaded to the system. (Manual sheet upload error handling for missing data).
- Static web hosting in S3 bucket (AWS).

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Front End Development

HTML 5 / CSS / JavaScript / React JS

Back End Development

Node JS

Microsoft Office

Microsoft Word / Microsoft Excel / Microsoft PowerPoint

Programming Languages

Python / Java / C Programming / C++

Databases

SQL/MYSQL / PostgresSQL / MongoDB

Tools

Android Studio / Git

PUBLICATIONS

Self-Driving Car using Convolutional Neural Network

[2020]

https://www.ijraset.com/fileserve.php?FID=27515

Published in International Journal for Research in Applied Science and Engineering Technology (IJRASET) Volume 8, Issue IV, April 2020

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Project presentation (V-HACK)

APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University [17/02/2019]

First prize for Life Source project in University level project presentation.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Malayalam

Other language(s): English